

,	– ACCA Global Companies – Financial A	nalyst – Feb 2019 till
(Part Qualified)		nalyst – Feb 2019 till
,		nalyst – Feb 2019 till
,		nalyst – Feb 2019 till
logi Group of C	Companies – Financial A	nalyst – Feb 2019 till
logi Group of C	Companies – Financial A	analyst – Feb 2019 till
ITecknologi Group of Companies – Financial Analyst – Feb 2019 till Present		
s issue		
ir Hussain & Associates	Audit Trainee	Jun 2017 – Dec 2018
	-	
	ir Hussain & Associates	ir Hussain & Audit Trainee

send it.

Ammar Bin Amir

Financial Analyst

Highly motivated and goal-driven Financial Analyst skilled in collecting, monitoring and studying data to analyze financial status and recommend business strategy. Experienced in qualitative and quantitative analysis, contract management and forecasting. Tech-savvy in use of spreadsheets, accounting and financial management software.

Skills

Data Analysis

Microsoft Office Suite

Operations Analysis

Business Planning

Operations management

Financial Analysis

Strategic financial planning

Work History

2023-02 - Current

Financial Analyst

ITecknologi Group Of Companies, Karachi

- Reviewed financial reports and streamlined operations to increase productivity and company profits by 10%.
- Collected data and developed detailed spreadsheets to identify trends and create revenue, profitability, and expense forecasts.

2021-02 - 2023-01

Operations Analyst

ITecknologi Group Of Companies, Karachi

- Designed plans to improve operations and suggested changes to systems for overall organization.
- Assessed operational performance to identify areas for improvement and able to decrease almost 15% of operational expense.

2020-02 - 2021-01

Assistant Manager - Finance

ITecknologi Group Of Companies, Karachi

- Prepared and managed large capital expenditure budgets to effectively handle infrastructure investment and long-term operations
- Maintained responsive organization with sustained revenue growth through industry forecast monitoring and deliberate financial planning

2019-08 - 2020-01 **F**

Finance Officer

ITecknologi Group Of Companies, Karachi

- Collaborated with team leaders to define standards, policies and procedures to meet company revenue goals.
- Monitored budget and revenue trends, compiling reports for company leadership to inform decision-making.

2019-02 - 2019-07

Management Trainee Officer

ITecknologi Group Of Companies, Karachi

- Assisted established management staff with operational oversight, business development, and process improvement strategies.
- Handled day-to-day customer or client questions via telephone or email.

2017-06 - 2018-12

Audit Trainee

Amir Hussain & Associates, Karachi

- Developed understanding of company audit methodology, approach and tools while working under supervision of licensed auditors.
- Analyzed information of payments to vendors against contracts to find overpayments, writing claims to retrieve over payments from clients.

Education

2018-10 - Current

ACCA (Part Quaified)

ACCA Global - Karachi

2017-01 - 2018-06

Foundation Diploma in Accountancy: Accounting

Tabani's School Of Accountancy - Karachi

2015-01 - 2016-12

Intermediate

S.M. Government Science College - Karachi

2013-01 - 2014-12

Matric

S.M Public Academy - Karachi

Languages

English

Urdu

Software

Quickbook

Oracle